import 'package:quiz_app_tutorial/models/question.dart';

List<Question> swift_questions = [
  Question(
    question: 'Q. What is Swift’s type inference?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      ' It allows developers to assign a variable without specifying its data type.',
      ' It allows developers to assign a variable with only one data type.',
      ' It allows developers to assign a variable with multiple data types.',
      ' It doesn’t allow developers to assign a variable without specifying its data type.',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: 'Q. What is a protocol in Swift?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      ' A blueprint for a class, struct, or enumeration',
      ' A way to define properties and methods for a specific type',
      ' A collection of related variables and functions',
      ' A way to organize code into reusable components',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: 'Q. What is the difference between a class and a struct in Swift?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      ' A class can inherit from another class, and a struct can’t.',
      ' A class is a reference type, and a struct is a value type.',
      ' A class has a default initializer, and a struct doesn’t.',
      ' A class is used for storing data, and a struct is used for defining behavior.',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: 'Q. What is an optional in Swift?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      ' A way to define a property that must have a value.',
      ' A way to define a property that may or may not have a value.',
      ' A way to define a property that can’t have a value.',
      ' A way to define a property that must have a default value.',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: 'Q. Who is introduced Swift?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      ' Chris Lattner',
      ' Vikram Adve',
      ' Steve Jobs',
      ' Tanya Lattner',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: 'Q. Which of the following is true about Swift?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      ' Swift is an open-source programming language',
      ' Swift is used in iOS development',
      ' Swift can be compiled as a dynamic framework',
      ' All of the above',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: 'Q. Swift is an open-source programming language developed by?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      ' Google',
      ' Facebook',
      ' Apple',
      ' IBM',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: 'Q. What is the meaning of question mark "?" in Swift?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      ' used in function declaration',
      ' used in property declaration',
      ' used in loop declaration',
      ' used in parameter declaration',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
    'Q. In Swift4, functions can be categorized in __________ types.',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      ' 1',
      ' 2',
      ' 3',
      ' 4',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
    'Q.  A function inside a function is called a nested function in swift?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      ' TRUE',
      ' FALSE',
      ' Can be true or false',
      ' Can not say'
    ],
  ),
];
